<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>GilLabs</title>
 <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/feed/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/"/>
 <updated>2023-02-11T11:37:27-04:00</updated>
 <id>https://adrianogil.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Adriano Gil</name>
   <email>adrianogil.san@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The divisibility rule of 3</title>
   <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/2022/08/divisibility-of-3/"/>
   <updated>2022-08-26T10:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/2022/08/divisibility-of-3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While reviewing my daughter’s homework, I got to think a little bit about the divisibility rule of 3.  Actually, the basic operations have some interesting properties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the sum of any number to 9 preserve the sum of its digits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;any number multiplied by 3 results in a number which the sum of its digits will also be a multiple of 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’m going to analyze a little bit the reasons behind each of these properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-the-sum-of-any-number-to-9-preserve-the-sum-of-its-digits&quot;&gt;1) the sum of any number to 9 preserve the sum of its digits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the operation below&lt;/p&gt;

\[A + 9 = B\]

&lt;p&gt;The sum of digits of A will be equal to the sum of digits of B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at some examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example 1.1:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

\[15 + 9 = 24\]

&lt;p&gt;the sum of the digits of $15$ will be equal to the sum of the digits of the resulting value $24$ ($2 + 4 = 6$)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example 1.2:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

\[71 + 9 = 80\]

&lt;p&gt;$7 + 1$ is equal to $8 + 0$, both $8$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-any-number-multiplied-by-3-results-in-a-number-which-the-sum-of-its-digits-will-also-be-a-multiple-of-3&quot;&gt;2) any number multiplied by 3 results in a number which the sum of its digits will also be a multiple of 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the operation&lt;/p&gt;

\[A * 3 = B\]

&lt;p&gt;this property implies that the sum of the digits of B will necessary be a multiple of $3$. As we can see in the examples below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example 2.1:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

\[24 * 3 = 72\]

&lt;p&gt;As we can notice the sum of the digits of $72$ is $7 + 2 = 9$, a multiple of 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example 2.2:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

\[19*3 = 57\]

&lt;p&gt;the sum of digits of $57$ is $5 + 7 = 12$, also a multiple of 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-deep-dive-of-the-divisibility-rule-of-3&quot;&gt;A deep dive of the divisibility rule of 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In elementary school we learn the divisibility rule of 3 and accept that it happens without really understanding why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TIL that the property 2 is derived of property 1, i.e, when multiplying a number by $3$ it also means a sum with $9$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the multiplication is actually a sequence of sum operations, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a simple operation like&lt;/p&gt;

\[3 * 4 = 12\]

&lt;p&gt;can also be expressed as a sequence of sum&lt;/p&gt;

\[3 + 3 + 3 + 3 = 12\]

&lt;p&gt;and can be rearranged to be a sum with $9$&lt;/p&gt;

\[9 + 3 = 12\]

&lt;p&gt;Let me show other examples in which multiplication by 3 reveals to be a sum with $9$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example 3.1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

\[3*5 = 3+3+3+3+3 = 9+6 = 15.\]

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example 3.2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

\[3*6 = 3+3+3+3+3+3 = 9+9 = 18\]

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multiplying-by-3-means-a-sum-between-a-number-k-plus-9&quot;&gt;Multiplying by 3 means a sum between a number k plus 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, we can conclude that the property 1 is the reason behind property 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the multiplication by $3$ implies a sum between a number $k$ plus $9$, the property 1 garantees that the sum of the digits of $k$ will be preserved and as $k$ is a multiple of 3, the sum of the digits of the result will also be a multiple of 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally Crazy, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below we can see a proof:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering any real number $x &amp;gt; 3$ and a $k = x - 3$:&lt;/p&gt;

\[3*x = 3*(k+3) = 3*k+9\]

&lt;p&gt;As $3 * k$ is a multiple of 3, by the rules of property 1, it’s implied that the digits of $3 * k + 9$ will also be multiple of $3$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-reason-behind-property-1&quot;&gt;What’s the reason behind property 1?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth to note that it happens because to sum with $9$ is the same thing to add $10$ and to subtract $1$ at same time, i.e., increasing one in second digit and decreasing one in first digit, what does not change the sum of digits ($ +1 - 1 = 0$).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also generalize that the property 2 happens with all numeral system with the following number of digits:&lt;/p&gt;

\[3 * N + 1\]

&lt;p&gt;for instance, decimal and hexadecimal numeral systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the number that follows the property 1 is always the maximum digit of the numeral system minus $1$: so it is $9$ for decimal numeral system and $F$ for hexadecimal numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Unity 101: A simple Space Invaders without coding</title>
   <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/2017/01/space-invaders/"/>
   <updated>2017-01-31T21:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/2017/01/space-invaders</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi guys,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are going to create a simplified version of Space Invaders using &lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt;. Programming is not scope of this tutorial. So we are using few scripts for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adrianogil/VisualBehaviors&quot;&gt;Visual Programming&lt;/a&gt; (actually condition-based scripts) I made for teaching Unity at my local university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- New project --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/00_first_screen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start creating a new project inside &lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt; editor by pressing &lt;i&gt;new&lt;/i&gt; button in the start screen. Now, let’s naming the project ‘MyGame’ and we can also define the project path where Unity is going to create all default initial project files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/01_new_project.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“MyGame” project created successfully! In the next figure, we can see the filesystem where &lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt; created three directories: Assets, Library and ProjectSettings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Assets&lt;/b&gt; is where we should put files we’d like to use in our game: scripts, spritesheets, textures, 3d models, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Library&lt;/b&gt; is used by &lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt; for generating assets for each build target. So here we are going to find the real spritesheets files that will be loaded by our game considering the configuration we choose. For example, we can choose a downscaled resolution for Android target and a heavier compression and resolution for Desktop target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;ProjectSettings&lt;/b&gt; stores our project configuration: project name and version, tags and layers systems, build targets, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Temp&lt;/b&gt; is a temporary folder for assembling our necessary files into final build executable (.exe, .app, .apk, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell: &lt;b&gt;Assets&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;ProjectSetttings&lt;/b&gt; are meant for files and configurations that will be changed by ourselves while developing a game. &lt;b&gt;Library&lt;/b&gt; e &lt;b&gt;Temp&lt;/b&gt; are only for &lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt; internal stuff, we should not change anything and neither add them to version control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/02_file_system_project.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A important thing to understand is that &lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt; projects are made of scenes. Which scene corresponds to a part of the game experience, like for example, a menu scene, level 1 scene, boss level scene, etc. Inside each scene we can find a lot of objects that are meant to player interact with, like menus, characters, power-ups items. These objects are known as &lt;i&gt;GameObjects&lt;/i&gt;. And each &lt;i&gt;GameObject&lt;/i&gt; have few components that allows to change its main characteristics. We are going to understand better in the next steps of this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Unity&lt;/i&gt; interface is comprised by these main tabs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt;: shows which GameObjects are in scene.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspector&lt;/strong&gt;: allows to ‘inspect GameObjects’, to see its components and properties or to change project and assets configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project&lt;/strong&gt;: mirrors the filesystem in path ‘MyGame/Assets/’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scene&lt;/strong&gt;: is a visualization into a specific point of game scene, where we can see and place GameObjects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game&lt;/strong&gt;: depicts the actual rendered game, the game being executed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Console&lt;/strong&gt;: an important tab for development, shows scritpts warnings and errors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AssetStore&lt;/strong&gt;: where we can download, buy and sell game assets of any type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/02_unity.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the default tab layout. We can change it in the top right dropdown menu. Each option has a different tab layout. In addition we can also move freely our tabs and create and create our own layout by clicking ‘Save Layout’ option. In the image I’ve create my ‘CrazyLayout’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/03_unity_layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far our game is comprised by two &lt;i&gt;GameObjecs&lt;/i&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;“Main Camera”&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;“Directional Light”&lt;/strong&gt;. The list of &lt;i&gt;GameObjecs&lt;/i&gt; can be seen in Hierarchy tab:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/04_initial_hierarchy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;i&gt;GameObject&lt;/i&gt; there are few components: Transform, Camera, GUILayer, FlareLayer and AudioListener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/05_main_camera_gameobject.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt; component allows to render the game. It’s like a way to see what’s happening in game execution for a given position. Just like a real camera, it films our game scene and presents it to the player to be seen in &lt;strong&gt;Game&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/06_camera_component.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt; component has a very important role: it defines the position, rotation and scale of GameObjects in scene space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/07_transform_component.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s create few folders in &lt;i&gt;Project&lt;/i&gt; tab. Usually it’s recommended to follow a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CiroContns/status/831547413290766338&quot;&gt;folder naming structure&lt;/a&gt; to ease the task of searching for assets while the projects grows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/08_create_folder.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project we are going to use the following folders: Prefabs, Scenes and Scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/09_folders_created.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s save our scene in &lt;em&gt;Scenes/Game.unity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/10_save_scene.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unity&lt;/em&gt; has basic 3d elements (cube, sphere, cylinder, …) that we can use in our games. By clicking with right mouse button we see the options of the figure below and add the cube into game scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/11_create_cube.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Hierarchy&lt;/em&gt; tab we can check our added cube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/12_cube_gameobject.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in &lt;strong&gt;Inspector&lt;/strong&gt; tab we can see its components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt;: stores position, rotation and scale changes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MeshFilter&lt;/strong&gt;: has information about object 3D geometry (aka. Mesh)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BoxCollider&lt;/strong&gt;: an important component to detect collisions during game execution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MeshRenderer&lt;/strong&gt;: renders our cube using geometry information (Mesh data) from MeshFilter component and using informations from &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/Materials.html&quot;&gt;Materials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/13_cube_components.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can change cube position by editing &lt;strong&gt;Position&lt;/strong&gt; field of &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt; component. It’s also possible to just select and move arrows that shows up when selecting the cube. That kind of visual element is called &lt;strong&gt;Gizmo&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/14_cube_transform.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When interacting with those red, blue and green &lt;strong&gt;Gizmo&lt;/strong&gt; we can see the cube moving in X,Z,Y axises. We also see the changes taking effect on &lt;strong&gt;Position&lt;/strong&gt; field of &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An useful tip: we can reset all modifications on transform by choosing &lt;strong&gt;Reset&lt;/strong&gt; from component options (Top right small engine icon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/15_transform_reset.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ease our task of manipulating cubes, we are going to change &lt;em&gt;snap&lt;/em&gt; configuration. In &lt;em&gt;snap&lt;/em&gt; mode our cube can be dragged by a fixed amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/16_snap_settings_menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Snap Settings&lt;/strong&gt; window we can configure our GameObjects movement in &lt;em&gt;snap&lt;/em&gt; movement. For now let’s leave the default settings as we can see in figure below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/17_snap_settings_window.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When pressing &lt;em&gt;Ctrl+D&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Cmd+D&lt;/em&gt; we can clone the selected GameObject. And when pressing &lt;em&gt;Ctrl/Cmd&lt;/em&gt; we move GameObjects in &lt;em&gt;snap&lt;/em&gt; increments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/18_cube_clone.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By cloning 13 cubes, i.e, pressing &lt;em&gt;Ctrl+D&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Cmd+D&lt;/em&gt;, we can make a line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/19_cubes_selection.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Empty&lt;/strong&gt; option allows to create an empty GameObject with only Transform component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/20_create_empty.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s rename the empty &lt;em&gt;GameObject&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Line&lt;/em&gt; and then reset &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt; component to its default values. After selecting all cubes, we can drag them into &lt;em&gt;Line GameObject&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt; tab. &lt;em&gt;Line&lt;/em&gt; is now the parent of all cubes. When selecting or moving &lt;em&gt;Line&lt;/em&gt; we are also moving its children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/21_create_lines.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/ViewModes.html&quot;&gt;scene shading options&lt;/a&gt; we can achieve a better visualization for our cubes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/22_shading_mode.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we clone the &lt;em&gt;Line GameObject&lt;/em&gt;, what means we are also cloning all its 13 children cubes. In this way we can create two more lines and drag them up. And when select a specific cube we can also delete it by &lt;em&gt;del/Cmd+del&lt;/em&gt;. So by repeating these basic steps, we can get the following structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/23_copy_lines.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we copy one more line to get the body of our character. To ease manipulating these objects, let’s create an empty &lt;em&gt;Body GameObject&lt;/em&gt;, reset its Transform and put &lt;em&gt;Line&lt;/em&gt; objects inside it as children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/24_finished_body.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the antenna we need to copy only one cube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/25_started_antenna.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s create an empty &lt;em&gt;GameObject Antenna&lt;/em&gt; and reset its &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt; and parenting that last created cube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/26_antenna_empty.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloning few more cubes we finish our &lt;em&gt;Antenna&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/27_finished_antenna.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to create &lt;em&gt;Claws GameObject&lt;/em&gt; and reset its &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/28_claws_empty.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clonning few more cubes as arranged in the below image, we finished the claws of our character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/29_claws_cubes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have a &lt;em&gt;Space Invader&lt;/em&gt;. To ease manipulating it, let’s create an empty &lt;em&gt;Cubes GameObject&lt;/em&gt;, reset its &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt; and drag &lt;em&gt;Body, Antenna and Claws&lt;/em&gt; into it. Then we can finally create a &lt;em&gt;SpaceInvader GameObject&lt;/em&gt;, reset its &lt;strong&gt;Transform&lt;/strong&gt; and parenting all cubes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/30_space_invaders_cubes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By selecting Cubes let’s change its scale to (0.2, 0.2, 0.2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/31_downscale_invader.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By clicking in &lt;strong&gt;Game&lt;/strong&gt; tab we can see how our character is going to be seen by the player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/32_invader_game_tab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt; let’s change the propriety &lt;em&gt;Clear Flags&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;Solid&lt;/em&gt; Color and &lt;em&gt;background color&lt;/em&gt; to (0,0,0,0).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/33_camera_clear_flags.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloning and creating new empty &lt;em&gt;GameObjects&lt;/em&gt; as we did in previous steps, we have our &lt;em&gt;Player GameObject&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/34_player_cubes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Game&lt;/strong&gt; tab we can see our game characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/35_player_game_tab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add movement to our game, let’s use some scripts I’ve made beforehand from my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adrianogil/VisualBehaviors&quot;&gt;Visual Behaviors project&lt;/a&gt;. Download or clone this project into Scripts folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/36_copy_scripts.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By inspecting &lt;em&gt;SpaceInvader GameObject&lt;/em&gt; we can add new components by pressing &lt;em&gt;Add Component&lt;/em&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/37_add_component.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s add Move script (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adrianogil/VisualBehaviors/blob/master/Move.cs&quot;&gt;Visual Behaviors&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/38_add_move_invader.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s configure Move script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/39_callevent_invader.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CallEvent&lt;/em&gt; script allows to change another scripts behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/40_configure_callevent.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside &lt;em&gt;Action&lt;/em&gt; block, let’s press + button to add an action. So we select a &lt;em&gt;GameObject&lt;/em&gt; that should have its behavior changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/41_configure_callevent.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s choose which component method we are going to change. Let’s call &lt;em&gt;ChangeDirectionX&lt;/em&gt;, a method that allows to invert current movement direction of &lt;em&gt;Move&lt;/em&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/42_configure_callevent.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Player movement can done by two Move scripts: one for right direction and another for left direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/43_move_player.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we create &lt;em&gt;Bullets GameObject&lt;/em&gt; as depicted in below image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/44_bullets_gameobject.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s add the &lt;em&gt;Move&lt;/em&gt; script to Bullets in order to move up the bullets towards space invaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/45_bullets_move.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By dragging &lt;em&gt;Bullets&lt;/em&gt; into &lt;strong&gt;Project&lt;/strong&gt; tab we can create a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.unity3d.com/Manual/Prefabs.html&quot;&gt;prefab&lt;/a&gt;, a pre-fabricated object that can be replicated and instantiated during game execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/46_bullets_prefab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s change the &lt;strong&gt;layer&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Bullets GameObject&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/47_edit_settings_layers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s create the &lt;em&gt;Bullets&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;layer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/48_tags_and_layers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then change the &lt;strong&gt;Bullets&lt;/strong&gt; prefab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/49_bullets_add_layer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When adding &lt;em&gt;Generate&lt;/em&gt; script to &lt;em&gt;Player GameObject&lt;/em&gt; we can allow our player to shoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/50_player_gen_bullets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;SpaceInvader GameObject&lt;/em&gt; we are going to add &lt;em&gt;DestroyMe&lt;/em&gt; script. Let’s configure our enemy to be destroyed every time it touches a bullet, I mean a &lt;em&gt;GameObject&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;Bullets&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;layer&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To collision be detected, we need a &lt;strong&gt;BoxCollider&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;RigidBody&lt;/strong&gt; components. Let’s freeze &lt;strong&gt;Rigidbody&lt;/strong&gt; rotation and define gravity as zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/51_invader_collision.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t forget to activate &lt;em&gt;isTrigger&lt;/em&gt; checkbox in &lt;strong&gt;BoxCollider&lt;/strong&gt; of our enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/52_invader_collider.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s add a trigger-enabled &lt;strong&gt;BoxCollider&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Bullet GameObject&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017-02-12-visualbehaviors/53_bullets_collider.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tela inicial&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we achieved a working Space Invader! Congrats for your first &lt;em&gt;Unity&lt;/em&gt; game!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Kuarup: a Global Game Jam 2016 game</title>
   <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/2016/01/global-game-jam-2016/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-10T14:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/2016/01/global-game-jam-2016</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I had the privilege of participating in one of the most popular game jams ever: the &lt;a href=&quot;http://globalgamejam.org/&quot;&gt;Global Game Jam&lt;/a&gt;. I was lucky enough to work with a team of incredibly talented individuals from the Samsung Institute and Samsung OCEAN. Our designer, Rafael Lima, and developers, Bruno Araujo, Germano Assis, and Marcus Brandt, were all exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the game jam began, the theme “Ritual” was revealed. With this in mind, we created a colorful puzzle game centered around the idea of sacrificing cute monsters. We interpreted “ritual” as repeating tasks, magic, and sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-02-14-ggj16/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;A game level on Kuarup&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role in the project was focused on the main gameplay features, including the logic behind block falling and eye-catching animations. I also worked on procedurally generating the adorable monster blocks. The challenge was ensuring that each level was always solvable. To achieve this, we employed a pseudo-random method and implemented a power-up mechanic that allowed players to remove blocks of a specific color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game we created during the Global Game Jam is now available for download on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pxlsquadgames.kuarup&quot;&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt;.  Don’t miss out on the chance to play this unique puzzle game filled with cute monsters and color-based challenges!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to my team for such a fantastic project and hope that we get the opportunity to work together again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the next game jam!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Install Theano, Blocks and Fuel</title>
   <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/2016/01/install-block-fuel-theano/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-10T14:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/2016/01/install-block-fuel-theano</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The very first step to develop a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning&quot;&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/a&gt; experiment - if you don’t want to code everything from scratch - is to look for a proper 3rd party component that provides a straightforward interface and a great performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In python, there are a lot of frameworks and libraries to work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deep_learning&quot;&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/a&gt;. After I had participated in a course taught by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/laurent-dinh&quot;&gt;Laurent Dihn&lt;/a&gt; from University of Montreal, I was introduced to the combined toolkit of Theano, Blocks and Fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://deeplearning.net/software/theano/&quot;&gt;Theano&lt;/a&gt; is a very known mathematical python library used for deep learning. This library contains a lot of useful methods to simplify model generation like using derivative of symbolic functions. Due to its bindings with PyCuda, Theano allows to use the same code to evaluate on CPU or GPU only by changing a flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks is a set of utilitary scripts that easen some tasks on Theano, like model generation, load and training data, and visualizing results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel is data processing library that handles some neat things like download and parse image datasets into numpy arrays. One of its advantage is a same interface that can handle a lot different types of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installing-on-windows&quot;&gt;Installing on Windows&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some useful tips on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/MachineLearning/comments/3hkv2b/most_recent_way_to_install_theano_for_windows_10/&quot;&gt;this reddit post&lt;/a&gt; and I have tested it on Windows 8.1 and Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is download and install the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.continuum.io/downloads&quot;&gt;Windows version of Anaconda&lt;/a&gt;. After a simple installation wizard, we need to install the required libraries for Theano. Thanks to Anaconda, we can use a very simple command-line tool &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;conda&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Anaconda Prompt&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    conda &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;pip six nose numpy scipy graphviz
    conda &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;mingw libpython&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some necessary python libraries are pre-requisite to specific Theano functions, like drawing debug graphs of operation nodes, and can also be used in Blocks or Fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;pydot2 progressbar2 picklable-itertools&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theano can be installed using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;theano&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel can be downloaded directly from github repository: https://github.com/mila-udem/fuel. In order to install it, we need to run the script &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;fuel
    python setup.py &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel can be downloaded directly from github repository: https://github.com/mila-udem/blocks. In order to install it, we need to use python to execute the setuptools script &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;blocks
    python setup.py &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-01-10-installing/mac-terminal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Testing Theano on Anaconda Prompt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installing-on-osx&quot;&gt;Installing on OSX&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://deeplearning.net/software/theano/install.html#mac-os&quot;&gt;Theano page about mac installation&lt;/a&gt; we can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.continuum.io/downloads&quot;&gt;download Anaconda&lt;/a&gt;  and then Theano can be installed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    conda &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;pip six nose numpy scipy graphviz
    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;pydot2
    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;Theano&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After downloading Fuel &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mila-udem/fuel&quot;&gt;on github page&lt;/a&gt;, inside its folder there is a script &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/code&gt; that handles the installation by means of setuptools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;fuel
    python setup.py &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once downloaded Blocks &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mila-udem/blocks&quot;&gt;from github page&lt;/a&gt;, you can install it by executing the setuptools script &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;setup.py&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;blocks
    python setup.py &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-01-10-installing/mac-terminal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Theano on Mac Terminal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installing-on-ubuntu&quot;&gt;Installing on Ubuntu&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some installation steps are published on &lt;a href=&quot;http://deeplearning.net/software/theano/install_ubuntu.html#install-ubuntu&quot;&gt;Theano site&lt;/a&gt;, so by following it I easily managed to install it on Ubuntu 14.10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download and e install all requisites of the libraries using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;sudo &lt;/span&gt;apt-get &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;python-numpy python-scipy python-dev python-pip python-nose g++ libopenblas-dev git gfortran libhdf5-dev graphviz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Theano can be installed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;Theano&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuel library can be also installed using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; directly from github repository:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;git+git://github.com/mila-udem/fuel.git &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks library also is installed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;    pip &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;install &lt;/span&gt;git+git://github.com/mila-udem/blocks.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-01-10-installing/ubuntu-terminal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Running Theano on Ubuntu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;installing-a-python-ide&quot;&gt;Installing a Python IDE&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some good experiences using PyDev and Eclipse, I recomend this light version &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Liclipse&lt;/code&gt;: http://www.liclipse.com/download.html. Some other good options can be found in: http://pedrokroger.net/choosing-best-python-ide/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2016-01-10-installing/ubuntu-liclipse.png&quot; alt=&quot;LiClipse IDE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World!</title>
   <link href="https://adrianogil.github.io/2016/01/hello-world/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T09:02:47-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://adrianogil.github.io/blog/2016/01/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s my personal blog about my researches and some development notes. I guess every tech guy should have a blog. Well, after some years, I decided finally to start mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, who am I? Well, I’m a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/21219242/CV/adrianogil_cv_en.pdf&quot;&gt;mobile developer&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://scholar.google.com.br/citations?user=n6RoXpAAAAAJ&quot;&gt;Game AI researcher&lt;/a&gt;.  I have a master in Electric Engineering and a BSc. in Computer Engineering at Federal University of Amazonas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interests lies in playing and developing games (Mobile and Desktop). In the next posts I’ll describe some of my projects related to game development, image processing research and machine learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
